本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：小松狮   joanna   silmar   小路      校对：小路
特效：Will     时间轴：虫不知      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第十集
你不会今天还想去工作吧
You're not thinking about going to work today, are you?
可能会的
Thought I would.
吸入器好像还挺管用的
That inhaler really seems to be doing the trick.
-怎么了  -这星期就休息吧
- What? - Just take the rest of the week.
求你了
Please.
这是你应得的
You've earned it.
别把自己逼太紧
Don't push it.
另外  我还想你为这周末作准备
Besides, I want you well for the weekend.
妈妈想要开  派对
Mom wants to par-tay.
只是个小聚会  仅此而已
It's just a little get-together, that's all.
有可能在周日下午
Sunday afternoon, maybe?
不会很隆重  就家人和一些朋友
Nothing too big. Just family and a few friends.
我们有很多值得庆祝的事
We've got a lot to celebrate.
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
听起来不错
Sounds good.
现在
Now,
你今天打算干什么
What are you supposed to do today?
什么也不做
Nothing.
很好
Excellent.
小精灵告诉你应该再小睡一会儿
Brownie points for taking a nap.
能出来见面吗
Can you meet?
我还以为你可能
I thought maybe you...
可能已经
Might have, you know,
不在了
Kicked.
驾鹤西去了
Signed off.
我都在看讣告
I was even checking the obits.
还没那么好的运气
No such luck.
那情况怎么样
So where does it stand?
咳嗽带血  还说
Coughing up blood, giving speeches like,
"这是我应得的  我是个混蛋"
"I deserve this. I'm an asshole."
结果怎么样
What's the upshot?
结果
The upshot.
结果就是我患了放射性肺炎
The upshot is that I have radiation pneumonitis.
该死
Damn.
实际上并没有听起来那么糟
Actually, it's not as bad as it sounds.
是很常见的并发症  很容易治愈
It's a fairly common occurrence, easily treated.
是个好消息
The news is all good.
你说好是什么意思
What do you mean, good?
就是指治好了吗
You mean, like, good good?
还是说  症状部分缓解
You mean, like, remission good?
症状缓解
Remission.
不是说我完全好了
Not to imply I'm cured.
我现在还是有癌症
I still have cancer.
但肿瘤组织已经减小了很多
But there's been a significant reduction in the tumors.
有多少
How significant?
80%
80%.
伙计
Dude!
不可能吧
No way!
不管怎样
Now, I'm not out of the woods yet,
我还没有脱离危险
Not by any stretch.
但他们老把"机会"挂在嘴边
"Options" is the word they keep bandying about.
太好了
That's awesome!
真的吗
Serious?
这太棒了
That's great, man.
我是说  我姑姑她  从没
I mean, my aunt, she never...
在你这样的阶段  我从没想过还会好
I mean, at your stage, I didn't think that could happen.
怀特老师  你太厉害了  哟
Mr. White, you kicked its ass, yo!
你肯定高兴坏了
You must be so psyched.
确实很高兴
Of course. I am.
现在我们
Now we...
我是说  我们接下来
I mean, what do we...
我差点忘了
I almost forgot.
那么
So,
你想怎样
How do you want to,
继续我们的生意
You know, proceed
在得到这么好的消息以后
In light of this kick-ass news?
我们要慢慢来  谨慎一些
We'll take our time and stay cautious.
把剩下的货都卖完
Sell off what we have.
然后
And then...
然后我想
Then I guess...
就结束吧
I'm done.
各就各位
Batter up!
大家注意
Everyone?
大家好  我想要敬大家一杯
Hey, you guys. I would like to make a toast,
用我的无酒精饮料
With my non-alcoholic beverage.
谁把音乐关一下
Somebody kill the music.
我知道一个小小的派对不能报答
I know one party can't begin to repay
你们所有的支持和
All your support and your...
你们那么多的帮助
Your many, many kindnesses.
不过
But then again,
汉克还是准备了些玛格丽塔鸡尾酒
Hank does make one mean margarita.
我们衷心感谢大家
We really do want to thank you.
过去的这几个月
These last few months have been...
婉转得说  是个考验
A challenging time, to put it mildly.
但沃尔特勇敢地克服了一切
But I have to say Walt's come through it like a champ.
亲爱的  我太为你感到骄傲了
Honey, I'm so proud of you.
我不能再说这些煽情的话了
I'm gonna stop with the sappy stuff.
但这是真的  确实如此
But it's true. It really is.
长久以来  第一次
And for the first time in a long time,
我们对未来满怀憧憬
We are so excited about the future.
无论如何
Anyway,
我还要向另外两个特殊的人
I want to also express my gratitude
表达我的感激之情
To two very special people
虽然他们今天不在这里
Who couldn't be here today.
但他们也感到遗憾并送来了贴心的祝福
But they send their regrets and their warm wishes.
格雷琴和埃利奥特·施瓦茨
Gretchen and Elliott Schwartz,
尽管你们不认识他们
For those of you who don't know them are...
他们真的是英雄
Well, they're heroes.
他们无限慷慨
They are incredibly generous
答应为沃尔特支付治疗费用
friends who made
此乃真朋友也
To pay for Walt's treatment.
他们说到做到
And they did.
所以
So...
为格雷琴和埃利奥特干一杯
To Gretchen and Elliott.
还有我们的主角  快
How about the man of the hour? Come on!
给我们讲两句
Speech!
说来有趣
It's kind of funny.
我得知自己被诊断为
When I got my diagnosis,
癌症时
Cancer,
我问自己
I said to myself,
"为什么是我"
"Why me?"
后来
And then,
那天当我知道好消息的时候
The other day, when I got the good news...
我问自己同样的问题
I said the same thing.
谢谢大家能来
Thank you for coming.
好好玩
Enjoy.
干杯
Cheers.
很鼓舞人
Inspirational.
我跟你说  我要给那帮混蛋
Tell you what. I gotta give those
一点新花样
Bastards points for originality
请听我娓娓道来
I'll tell you that much.
一个水银开关  9伏特电池
A little mercury switch, 9-volt battery,
五六盎司C4塑胶炸药
5 or 6 ounces of C4,
这帮毒贩们就这么狂欢的
That's how those cartel boys party.
可是为什么是海龟
But why a turtle?
这个最有意思了  它是
That's the best part. It was a...
我到底想说什么词来着
What the hell's the word I'm looking for?
不是隐喻  不是类比  是
Not a metaphor, not an analogy... it's a...
沃尔特  我想说什么词来着
Walt. What's the word I'm looking for?
管它呢  "托尔图加"
Anyway, "tortuga."
我们的线人就叫这个名字
That was the name of our snitch.
英文意思是"玳瑁"
Bean-speak for "tortoise."
玳瑁  海龟  你
Tortoise, turtle, what have you...
我自己都不知道有什么区别
I never knew the difference myself.
帮我满上  好吗  兄弟
Top me off there, will you, buddy?
不管怎么说
Anyway,
诗意化的
Poetic.
我猜  对  诗意化  诗意化说法
I guess, yeah. Poetic. It was poetic.
就是这个词  我猜就是这个词
That's the word. I guess that's the word.
喝吧
Go ahead.
最好别让你妈看见
Better not let your mom see.
我看见一根头发  或许是两根
I think I see a hair. Maybe two!
里面没虫子吧
There's no worm in this, right?
没有  这是龙舌兰
No. That would be mescal.
说起喝醉酒来
Talk about your hangovers, okay?
有一次我在乔治亚州的格林科
I was down in Glynco, Georgia.
东部  在那儿受训
Back east, doing some training.
有个枪支指导员
Had this firearm instructor who was...
他是个特纯朴的人
He was a good ol' boy.
好了  谢谢
There you go. Thanks.
我是说  这家伙喝起酒来
I mean, this guy could put them
就像他有两个肝脏似的  懂吗
Away like he had two livers, okay?
喝酒就像鱼喝水  喝醉的了鱼
Like a fish, okay? Like a drunk fish.
我们都灌龙舌兰灌懵了
We were drinking mescal stupid. But...
沃尔特  你这是干嘛
Hey... Hey. Walt. What are you doing there?
你看我像干嘛
What does it lookating. Come on.
这孩子才16岁
The kid's 16.
你要干嘛  争当年度最佳老爸
What are you, going for father of the year?
你看他干嘛
What are you looking at him for?
我们在庆祝呢  继续
We're celebrating. Come on.
听着  如果我是你的话
Listen, I'd take a pass on
这杯我就不喝
That one if I were you
别再教坏这孩子了
Think we've been bogarting this puppy long enough.
把酒瓶拿回来
Bring the bottle back.
对不起  老兄  恕难从命
Sorry, buddy. No can do.
我的儿子  我的酒  我的家
My son! My bottle! My house!
没事
It's all right.
你还等什么
What are you waiting for?
拿回来
Bring it back.
今天就这么着吧
Why don't we just call it a day?
行吗  兄弟
All right, pal?
没事了
We good?
酒瓶
The bottle.
马上给我
Now.
出什么事了
What's going on?
好了  宝贝
Here, sweetie.
这是你的脑子
This is your brain.
这是你吸毒之后的脑子
This is your brain on drugs.
你不该醒的
You weren't supposed to wake up.
永远别醒还是
Ever or...?
我本打算过会儿  你知道  端进去
I was just thinking that I'd bring it, you know, in.
要我回去躺着吗
You want me to go back to bed?
不用  我想那就有点儿
No. I guess that'd be kind of...
要帮忙吗
Need some help?
我能行
I got it.
你去坐着吧
Just have a seat.
有咖啡吗
Is there any coffee?
该死  稍等
Shit. One second.
至少这个让我来吧
At least let me do that.
我不想让你干一点儿活  明白吗
I don't want you to have to do anything, you know?
好了  成了
All right. Here.
好的那个给你
You take the good one.
这是墨西哥式煎蛋
It's Huevos Rancheros.
看得出来
I can tell.
叉子
Fork.
给你
There you go.
那你今天打算做什么
So what are you up to today?
工作吗  不管是什么工作
Working? Whatever that means.
我陪着你
I'm all yours.
真的
Really?
你好  我是斯凯勒  请留言  谢谢
Hey, this is Skyler. Please leave me a message. Thanks.
我只是想说
I just wanted to say that...
我们今晚谈谈
We'll talk tonight,
但是我想说
But I wanted to say that
我不知道昨天是怎么回事
I'm not exactly sure who that was yesterday,
但那不是我本意
But it wasn't me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我爱你
Love you.
我只是想说
I just wanted to say that...
我们今晚谈谈
We'll talk tonight,
-但是我想说  -你好啊
- But I wanted to say that... - Hey, there.
-谁带的吉拿棒[类似油条]  -我带的
- Who brought the churros? - That would be me.
如果放在家里
If I leave them at home, I'll wind
我会一个人全吃掉  所以
Up eating them myself. So...
其实是剩下的
They're actually leftovers.
我们给沃尔特开了个小聚会
We had a little get-together for Walt.
不是他生日  对吧
It wasn't his birthday, was it?
实际上
Actually,
沃尔特他
Walt's got...
他一直在...与癌症斗争
He's been... battling cancer.
上周我们收到了好消息
And last week, we got good news.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
但我们很乐观的
But we're really optimistic.
太好了
Great.
有好消息太好了
Good news is great.
是啊  确实是
Yeah, it is. It really is.
欢迎随时带好吃的来
Feel free to bring these any time.
我们这可有不少好东西
Got some real beauts.
C3型的加热效率是最高的
You cannot beat the thermal efficiency of the C3.
那么  无水箱的怎么样
Then again, what about tankless?
当然  我们有货
Sure. We got them.
不过好东西价钱也高
The good ones will really run up your price though.
你得多掏差不多一千二
Set you back about 1,200.
钱不是问题
It's not an issue.
需要上门安装的吧
You want installation, right?
不用  我自己装
No. I'm gonna do it myself?
真高兴听你这么说
That's what I like to hear.
还有这是谁  他还能无板冲浪吗
And who's this? This guy can surf without a board?
那是飞人
That's hover man.
他会冲浪  滑冰  滑翔
He can surf, skate, glide,
无所不能  因为他的双脚
Whatever, 'cause he's always got a
能喷射6英寸的空气流
6-inch cushion of air under his feet.
好酷  线条不错
That's cool. Great lines.
那这人又是谁  他有什么超能力
And this guy? What's his superpower?
这是袋鼠人
That's kanga man.
袋鼠人  半人半袋鼠吗
Kanga man. Half man, half kangaroo?
他袋子里的是谁
And who's this in his pouch?
他的小伙伴乔伊
His sidekick Joey.
他坐在袋子里到处行侠仗义
He rides around in his pouch and, you know,
打击犯罪
Fights crime.
这么说袋鼠人是女的
So that makes kanga-man a she.
你知道的  对吧
You know that, right?
只有母袋鼠才有袋子
Only female kangaroos have pouches.
对  我知道
Yeah.I know.
但你知道  这绝对是个男的
But, you know, it's definitely a dude.
他是经实验改造过的
He's a product of experimentation.
他很性感呢  臀型很好
He's kind of hot, I guess. Nice haunches.
还有这个呢
And this is?
这个是倒行人
It's Backwardo.
不对  等等  我更名叫逆行人了
Wait, no. I actually changed it to Rewindo.
总之  他倒退着走路
Anyways, he goes backwards.
他能让所有东西倒退着走
He can make everything go in reverse.
让时间倒退吗  像时空旅行那样
Time and stuff? Like time traveling?
不是   他就是倒着走路而已
No, he just walks backwards.
他倒着走路
He walks backwards.
这也算超能力吗  有什么用处
Is that a superpower? What good is that?
他能倒走走得很快
He does it, like, really fast.
比如有人拿着把刀对着他的时候  对吧
Look, say someone's coming at him with a knife. Right?
这就有用了  他就能倒退着逃得远远的
It's helpful.Then he can just zip backwards away from them.
我画这些的时候  还很小
I was a kid,when I drew all these.
差不多4年前的事了
It was, like, four years ago.
他们看起来跟你很像
They all look like you.
画里的人都是你
It's you in all of these.
真想知道心理医生见了这些会怎么说
I wonder what a shrink would say if he saw them.
少来了
Shut up.
好像你从不希望能拥有超能力一样
Like you never wanted a superpower.
是有人在敲你的门还是我的
Is that your door or mine?
我不知道
I don't know.
好像是我的
It sounds like mine.
我得走了
I gotta go.
去哪
Where?
等等  你这是去哪...
Hold up. Where are you...
珍妮
Jane
老爸
Hey, dad.
总算开门了
There you are.
宝贝
Hi, honey.
看到你车在  所以我相信你肯定在家
I saw your car, so I was pretty sure you were home.
抱歉  我在工作  带着耳机呢
Sorry. I was working. I had my headphones on.
终于意识到这不是鼓点声了
Finally realized that I wasn't the drum track?
是啊
Exactly.
我正好在附近
I was in the neighborhood.
想问你要不要跟我一起吃午餐去
Was wondering if you wanted to have some lunch
当然好
Sure.
-这是你爸爸吗  -是的
- This your dad? -Yes.
这是新房客
This is the new tenant.
唐纳德
Donald.
不好意思  有事找我吗
I'm sorry. Did you need something?
没有
No.
老爸  进屋坐吧  见到你太高兴了
Dad, why don't you come in? It was nice seeing you.
-很高兴见到你  -我也是
- It was nice to meet you. - Me, too.
老爸
Hey, dad.
儿子
Hey, son.
-提早放学回家了  -对
- Are you home early? - Yeah
老天
Oh, man.
今天过得还好吗
Did you have a good day?
现在好了  总算有热水了
Now it is. Finally, hot water.
不用再用有毒废水了
No more toxic waste.
是啊  的确是
Yes, indeed.
顶级装备  即开即热  尽情用好了
Top-of-the-line, on demand, unlimited supply.
太好了
Sweet.
想试试看吗
Want to take her for a spin?
你去厨房水槽边等着怎么样
Listen, why don't you go to the kitchen sink?
到了说一声  我再知会你
Let me know when you're ready, and I'll give you a holler.
指示灯  打开
The pilot... in.
点火  成了
Ignition. Bingo.
准备
Ready!
好了好了  放水吧
All right. Let her rip!
11万7千BTU热量[热量单位]
117,000 BTUs.
内置防腐通风装置
Built-in corrosion resistant draft reducer,
设有安全电热偶长明灯
Safety thermocouple at the pilot burner.
听上去真的不错  老爸
Sounds really good, dad.
还有节能装置
And the energy savings.
小心  小心  小心
Careful, careful, careful.
可能还需要调整一下
There's probably some adjustments
我会搞定的  你没事吧
I need to make there. Are you ok?
没事
I'm fine.
儿子  昨天的事...
Son, about yesterday...
抱歉我吐在泳池里了
I'm sorry about the pool.
这不是你的错  你一点都没错
That was not your fault. Not at all.
是你老爸自己丢人了
Your old man embarrassed himself,
我为自己的行为感到羞愧
And I'm not very proud of my behavior.
不得不说  我真觉得自己很蠢
I have to say I feel very foolish.
你和汉克姨父好像闹僵了
You and uncle Hank, you seemed pissed off.
我们没事的  一切都很好
We're fine. Everything's fine.
今天早上我打电话跟他道过歉了
I called him this morning and made my apologies.
但是  儿子  其实我最该道歉的人是你
But, son, I owe you an apology most of all.
我该考虑得更周全些
I should have used better judgment all around.
一开始让你喝酒  就是错的
Having you drink in the first place, it was not right,
对此我非常抱歉
And for that I'm very sorry.
但我一直在喝  对吧
But I kept up, right?
你和汉克叔叔...
You and uncle Hank.
我喝了三杯
I drank three.
我去把工具放放好
I have some tools to put away.
晚点想去看电影吗
You want to catch a movie later?
刚刚那是怎么回事
What was that all about?
什么
What?
刚才  你爸来的时候
Before. With your dad.
没什么呀
It wasn't about anything.
这么说完全是我误解了吗
So I totally just misread your total dis?
如果有什么  那也是我帮了你一个忙
If anything, I was doing you a favor.
帮忙
A favor?
我跟你提过  他是个凶悍的人
I told you.He's a hard-ass.
-他看起来对我挺和善  -额  好吧
- He seemed cool to me. - Yeah, well...
-到底怎么回事  -没什么事
- So what's the deal? - There's no deal.
我是在帮你  好吗  保护你
I was helping you out, okay? Protecting you.
-怎么说  -我是说
- How's that?  - I mean,
我让你这儿抽烟  随心所欲
I'm letting you smoke in here and everything.
我买了滤嘴
I bought a filter.
我觉得他知道得越少  对你越好
And I figured the less he knows, the better.
你刚表现的好像不认识我
You acted like you didn't even know me.
-所以  -你觉得我该表现的像
- So?  - You think I'm going to be all like,
"老爸  这是住隔壁的吸毒男
"Dad, meet the stoner guy who lives next door.
"顺便说一句  我跟他睡过"
"And by the way, I'm sleeping with him"?
你就这么想的吗
That's all you think you're doing?
-为什么你这么介意我老爸  -我才没有呢
- Why do you even care about my dad? - I don't!
很好  那我就不知道为啥还要谈论这个
Good. Then I don't know why we're talking about it.
我们  好吗  我说的是我们
Us. All right? I'm talking about us.
我们
Us.
你和我
You and me.
你和我算是谁
Who's you and me?
我出去下
I'm out of here.
老爸
Dad?
怎么了
What?
-你在干什么  -我们家烂了
- What are you doing? - We've got rot.
烂了
Rot?
我指给你看  这儿
I'll show you. Here.
好好看看
Take a look at that.
看见了没
See that?
之前见过吗
Ever seen anything like it?
-只是块木头  -是木头
- It's wood. - It's wood
上面却有很多子实体
that contains fruiting bodies.
子什么
Fruity what?
真菌  而且已经爆发了
Fungus. And it is on a rampage.
我真看不出有什么
I don't really see anything.
就这在那儿
Well, it's there.
你得从哪看  这儿
You just have to know where to look. Here.
然后你把它们都锯掉
Then you cut it all out.
你把它们锯掉  然后换上新的
You just cut it out and start fresh.
我得继续了
Well, better get to it.
整间屋子都会倒塌吗
Is the whole house gonna collapse or something?
如果锯掉这些那就不会了
Not if I can help it.
你打算升职吗  这么卖力干活  该回家了
You bucking for a promotion? Go home already.
我马上走
I will.
能问下
Can I just ask...
凯勒公司的账户吗
the Keller account.
凯勒公司的账户
Keller account...
在这张资产负债表里被列为流动资产
It's listed as a Current Asset on this balance sheet,
但是应收账款里
but the invoice was never presented to
却从没有该项发票  所以
accounts Receivable, so.
老天
God.
总有一天我都得把
One of these days I'm going to have to sort through
老爸的业务分下类
all the Dad stuff.
他总是有很多和小公司的业务往来
He had so many "Don't worry about it, pay me Friday"
诸如"别担心  周五结清"
Relationships with these little companies.
明天再解决吧
We'll figure it out tomorrow.
也许还搞不定
Or not.
好的
Right.
说真的  你不会想让我把你锁在这儿吧
Seriously, you're not gonna make me lock you in, are you?
我没事
I'm fine.
荷尔蒙的关系  老实说  最近老这样
It's hormones. Honestly. It happens all the time.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我猜只是
I guess it just
感觉一切如常
doesn't feel any different.
那个
The...
好消息
good news?
我是说
I mean,
没有任何改变
nothing's really changed.
只是延期了而已
It's just postponed.
隧道的尽头应该会有光线
There was supposed to be a light at the end of the tunnel.
但
But...
最近  感觉就像
lately, it just feels like...
隧道没有尽头
More tunnel.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我感觉自己太忘恩负义了
I just feel so damn ungrateful.
我不知道
I don't know.
对我来说  只是感冒
For me, it was the flu.
什么
What?
我老爸去世前精神抖擞
My dad rallied at the end.
我是说  也不是沃尔特这样的好消息
I mean, it wasn't the full-on good news Walt got,
情况不同  但我们高兴坏了
Different circumstances, but we were happy,
简直欣喜若狂
we were over the moon.
就在那个时候  我病了
And right then, I got sick.
流感  萎了好几天
Flu. Boom. Knocked me on my ass for days.
下不了床  动不了
Couldn't get out of bed, couldn't move.
很巧吧
Great timing.
我都没把这俩事放一块
And I wasn't even putting two and two together.
只是想
I was just thinking,
为何是现在
Why now?
死撑着
Being that rock...
死撑着只会让你失去一切
Being that rock takes everything you got.
你今天还去工作吗
Are you going to work today?
斯凯勒  那儿烂了
Skyler, there's rot.
我回去忙了
I work back
道歉娃娃
Apology Girl
该死
Damn!
-我真是笨手笨脚  -我来拣吧
- Clumsy. - I got it.
你不必这样
You don't have to do that.
你买错火柴了
You're buying the wrong matches.
-什么  -这些火柴  品种不对
- What? - Those matches. They're the wrong kind.
红磷应该从火柴盒擦条带上划得
Red phosphorous is found in the striker strips,
不该在火柴上的
Not the matches themselves.
你要买200根
You need to get the big 200-count box of
独立装的火柴
Individual matchbooks.
有更多的擦条带  明白吗
More striker strips. You understand?
这些火柴才一个擦条带
Those only have the one.
还有别在一个地方买所有东西
And don't buy everything in one place.
零碎着买
Do it piecemeal.
不同的商店采购不同的东西
Different items, different stores.
减少注意力
Attracts less attention.
听懂我说的了吗
Are you following me here?
就是他  那个家伙
There he is. That's the guy.
滚出我地盘
Stay out of my territory.